# KARTIKAY JAINWAL

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER



#### **ABOUT**

LONDON

07576681965

KJAINWAL.COM

in IN/KJAINWAL

YAKITRAK

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JAVASCRIPT | TYPESCRIPT REACT | REDUX NODE | EXPRESS | API JEST | CUCUMBER | CYPRESS HTML5 | CSS3 | SCSS MONGODB | POSTGRESQL DOCKER | GITHUB | AWS JAVA | C# | PYTHON

#### LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (NATIVE) HINDI (NATIVE)

# **INTERESTS**

UKULELE

READING

FITNESS

#### SUMMARY

Highly motivated fullstack software developer with a creative problem solving mindset gained from several years of industry experience. Hardworking and enthusiastic individual with a passion for technology and innovation. Ability to work with multiple programming languages and eager to learn more. Strong experience in fullstack JavaScript including TypeScript, React, Node, Express and more.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SAINSBURYS**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

01/2022 - PRESENT

- Developed features on full stack web applications using TypeScript, React, Redux, NodeJS. Extensively tested using react-testing-library, Jest, Cypress, Cucumber etc. Took responsibility for deployments on AWS.
- Maintained projects and supported on incidents raised for applications ensuring any issues are fixed and the corresponding teams are updated.
- Responsible for keeping the team aligned with meeting, sprint and support
  management responsibilities. Also supported junior members of the team and involved
  with interview process.
- Volunteered as Wellbeing champion to promote and disseminate information to colleagues regarding maintaining and improving wellbeing. This also involved providing listening ear for team members and signposting when required.

#### **TECH CITY VENTURES**

10/2020 - 12/2021

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Implemented core functionality across multiple web platforms, integrating APIs and developing new features in packages and microservices to support modular code design.
- Developed web applications or packages used JavaScript, React, Redux, React-Router, StorybookJS documentation, Node, Express, GItlab CI/CD, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes and Helm.
- Took ownership of projects working fullstack from frontend to backend to deployment (Used Agile methodology via JIRA to assign and track tasks)
- Supported junior developers and created tools to set standards and automate repetitive tasks

# **TRANSALIS** 07/2019 - 10/2020

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Integrated new EDI customers with existing solutions and developed bespoke solutions (create / consume REST APIs for large scale critical projects based on client requirements).
- Developed advanced fullstack CRUD web applications to allow non-EDI educated business staff to handle internal operations.
- Worked within teams and independently took ownership on multiple projects communicating with clients directly to identify project deliverables and meet deadlines (Using Trello to manage tasks and deadlines).
- Used a range of technologies depending on project or task including JavaScript, React, Node, Express, Java, MongoDB, and XSLT / JSON.

#### THE CARTO GROUP

09/2017 - 08/2018

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Created GIS based web applications for multiple projects and a large scale project (Using Trello to manage tasks and deadlines).
- Web applications utilised a Node Express Backend with a PostgreSQL database and a React Frontend using Redux and Material Design guidelines.
- Scripted tools to automate tedious processes using python.

# EDUCATION

# THE UNIVERSITY OF PORTSMOUTH

BSC(HONS) SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FIRST CLASSIFICATION

# **NEW COLLEGE**

BTEC LEVEL 3 SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TRIPLE DISTINCTION STAR

08/2015 - 07/2020

08/2013 - 07/2015